I forced the Flatmates team to
use the Yi for 24 hours to
program solutions that
would improve their work, and all of this
during our offsite in Livinho.
This is much more in this
weekly vlog.  Hi guys, I'm in Livho
with the whole Flatmates team.
You thought I'd sneak out after
the exit and escape to the Maldives, but
here I am, still in the trenches, still
grinding.  I never get tired.  Check
out Livigno, out of season, and
marvel at this super-
fantastic hotel.  The little room isn't badly made.
Look at this.  This is the entrance.  Here
's the closet, here's the bathroom, here's
me and above all downstairs is both the
restaurant and the stations where we're
working.  Fundamental because tomorrow there
will be a crazy Haton.  In fact,
since we are in the AI ​​era and there is more and
more talk about autonomous agents, about
AI that does everything for us,
I have also made several videos on the subject and
there are people at Flatmates, as
in all companies, some more,
some less expert in these topics,
I organized a whole
day accaton by freeing up everyone's schedule,
now that we are all together here at
Livinho, to force them to learn how to
use vibe coding,
automation, AI and to clash a bit
with these tools, because what I have
noted is that you certainly don't
learn to use these tools in a day
, but even just—I'm not saying
a day, even just an hour—is enough to
understand their potential.  If you've ever
used Replit, which I used to make
a video, you'll realize how little it
takes to create a
website, an automation, or something
like that.  By the way, this time we are
more than 30 people, every year we are more and
more, but we don't give up,
we continue to do the offsites.  I don't
even know how many of us there are in Flapms in total,
but I think between the core team, professionals,
etc., etc., we are more than 40
people.  Here offsite we are more than 30,
so it's really crazy.  And we've
colonized this crazy place
called Montiva Lodge that
houses us all in these
really, really nice rooms.  This is the
first day offsite Monday,
unfortunately it's already evening because I left
Sorrento this morning.  I spent a
weekend in Sorrento, beautiful,
wonderful, by the sea to relax a
bit.  Instead of going to the Maldives in
Sorrento, forgive me.  [laughter] And
so I've already screwed this first day
.  I'm so tired because I've put in
a million hours.  I
left Naples this morning at 8:00
, it's 7:00 in the evening, but I can't
sleep because I have to prepare
the Acaton for tomorrow.  Two, I have a lot of
work to finish.  Once we get to
dinner, we eat right away.  Typical food.
[music]
This Livo,
very beautiful.  We're talking about the ACatan
of tomorrow.   We're
already having fun.
How are you doing for tomorrow?   Very
rich.
What is being discussed at this table?  Ch We don't
talk about it.  We're talking about everyone.
What glass are we at?  You.
The first evening concludes with some games
prepared by Gigi, which every year are
surprisingly well attended, and
I'm very happy about that.
2 1
[laughter] Fr
Frank got up just as she left.
Fore
no.
Good morning friends, today is the big
day, a beautiful awakening in nature.
I'm very excited.
Attention, we also have
centrifuges.
[music]
Breakfast was good.  Now
the ACaton begins.  The boys divided themselves into
groups based on the groups I mentioned
last night.  I'm very curious.  The ACathon
has begun, all the teams, there are nine
teams, have got to work.  I went
around all the tables, it took me
an hour and a quarter, and for each team I
looked a little and listened to their ideas
, I suggested which one to
start with and also the best way to
attack the problem.  But I have to say,
all very cool ideas.  If we
developed every little piece we would
really cause devastation.  So I'm very
happy with how it started.  People
are families.  We have I have
done all the code and it tells me to
run it on class.   I do
n't know what it is because I
had it before on Google Apps script.  I
went to Cloud Code and it was like, "No,
don't put the script here, let's
run it on class."  Maybe you could argue with him,
ask him why.
My knowledge ends much earlier.
Wait, but how does the team
program with her?  Can everyone
program?  Absolutely not,
practically no one knows how to do it.  Do you
remember the video I made with
Repllit, the Vibe Coding website?
Go and see it.  I got myself
unlimited credits on Replit for the
day and gave them to all the
team members to vibe code their
solutions.  TO THE.  They could have used
any other tool if they wanted,
but it was especially useful for those starting
from scratch.  In fact, you don't need to know how
to program, just talk to the
Yi and [music] will do everything for
us.  We are the ones who have to direct it
and possibly ask for various
changes.  And if there's something we don't
understand, just ask.  Theoretically, you don't
need anyone else's help.  [music]
We got a little excited looking at
the visual identity of te l'atta.  What
project are you doing?
We're, let's say, automating
onboarding,
which is a big problem because
onboarding today is like in Sparta,
we throw you among lions and instead
we create our onboarding companion
and we now put our email,
let's suppose, okay, obviously it's
processing all the info and then it will give you
this screen like you're replacing
a colleague, if you have the name, it gives you the
overview.
Are you using repliit?
We are using replip.  Like you're new,
you just arrived, it gives you a
skim of Flatms information that it
's now editing.  Who does what,
so the organizational chart, you the processes
we use or if a colleague takes over, he
gives you what he has done in the last few
months, what he has been involved in and the various
tasks you will have to do.  In the meantime,
lunch also arrived.  We have
sandwiches, lasagna, pasta with sauce.
But what are you up to?  We are creating
our own people, they will help us with the
production and creativity of the
content, videos and everything.
A kind of AI producer, your
agent who organizes video productions
.
Correct.
In the meantime Michele arrived.
I have arrived.
What are these vibes like?
Positive?  Yes, they were all happy.
There is beautiful scenery.
What is the difficulty?
We're
iteratively brainstorming with Cloud to get him to tell us
what to do.  What are you
building?
A platform
without intelligence.  They're making an
outbound machine.
Ah, wow, that's cool.  We are becoming what
we have always hated.
What are you doing?
We are creating a sort of Gant for
studio work,
an automation to manage projects,
especially new projects,
incoming projects, therefore from receiving the
brief to the finished proposal.
As you get more structured and have more
customers, more suppliers, more employees,
you create the LLC, a lot of
more paperwork also arises and you underestimate the
time wasted on this
paperwork.  And that's why, since
we're in the new millennium, it makes sense
to use the best technological tools
available, so that we have to go
crazy as little as possible.  As
for my company current account, I
use Vivid not only because it gives me
interest on my cash, which is no
small feat for company accounts, but also because
I can pay directly from the F24 IF,
I can upload receipts and invoices
so my accountant has
everything ready and in order, I can
obviously schedule bank transfers,
I can issue cards for my employees and
manage spending limits for each employee, and I can
activate and deactivate
cards in real time.  And then
the use is simple, you can see that it is not
a 90s IUX, but it is designed for
people like me who on the one hand
need seriousness because they manage
a company that is constantly growing and they
cannot afford for things to
break.  But on the other hand, there are
advantages to having a smart account that
isn't necessarily something for kids, and
so even being able to simply see
a summary of what I've spent for the month
isn't bad.  And then on Vivid it's all
in one.  I can even
invest my money if I want in
stocks, bonds, ETFs, whatever I
want.  In short, if you are an entrepreneur
you must try Vivid.  I'll leave the link
in the description in the first comment and
also in the QR code you see on the screen.
Lunch made blocked for a moment
gifts.  We were given
barburs, one for each member of
this site.
Amazing, a
very expensive gift.
Very expensive.
Congratulations to Fra Russo and Fiore because
they created
a masterpiece.
I mean,
in the meantime it got dark, I made
a lot of calls and I also
forgot to vlog because in the
meantime I accidentally disconnected
replies from all the people who
were using it and I spent an hour
cursing trying to figure out how to give it
back to them.  I should have succeeded.
Here are the NCCs who are
taking us to dinner.  I still have to get
mine.  By the time they get to the restaurant, most
of the teams have finished, although there are
a few latecomers who are still
finishing up.  How is it going?
Balls, but we'll make it.  We have some
final rework to do.
Are you satisfied with your work?
Very.  We will win.   We do
n't say anything.  Are you finished?   I
'm out of tokens on Cloud.  Are you
finished?
Yes, we're done.
Are you satisfied?
Very.
Watch out, we still have someone
finishing up here.
No, I'm doing the post Aathon and the
questions about you.
Ah, are you finished?
Yes, yes, yes, we're done.  Our
HR brain is ready to surprise you.
How is it going here?  Are you finished?
Our pack is very strong.  We have
a powerful vision.
How are we doing?  Achaton.  Well, we're
happy.
At that point, even though it was almost
midnight and a good portion of the team
had drunk a good portion of
alcohol, we set off with the Peaches.  For the
first team, Maria Vittoria, a
sales representative at Flatmates, speaks. She's fresh out of the woodwork,
and her team asked themselves what
an AI agent would do if it were a Flatmates sales representative
.  He would do research to understand
which companies are eligible to
offer our services and would
contact them.
Let's focus and develop software
that is focused on creating
Leading Bound.  If a brand receives
an investment today, I need to know
that they have budget to spend, I need to
know it immediately.  However, monitor
market news and therefore have a
general overview of
all the newsletters and information
that are passed on.  So he has a platform and
what does he do?  Every day he analyzes the
sources we have to provide him—
newsletters,
marketing sources, information on LinkedIn—and
gives us a list of
the top clients to contact because they've
had an event that requires them to be
contacted, maybe they've
received some investment budget
, or a role has changed, like a
marketing manager within the company.  Once
the email is sent, if the
customer doesn't respond, it monitors and
then replies to the email.  So we
called him Mastrota.  This
is kind of the main view, so
the idea is that every sales person
opens their page in the morning, sees
the tasks to be done, the
useful leads we authorize, and
it automatically sets up the whole
contact process.  [applause]
[cheering]
Second team presented by Stefano Head
of Studio and in fact he created a
solution specifically for his
team.  A management system to manage all the
projects that come up when
everyone is working on something, but
a competition or an unexpected request arrives
.  Presentation with
initial video.
A brief.  The images are in the Sash and
data.  I extract them and embed them
directly into the HTML with base 64.
Welcome to the Stranger Team.  It's the tool
for briefs that turn you upside down.
A new proposal arrives that is a
competition and it goes, let's say, to overlap with
the oning of our projects, right?  So
we created a tool, it's a sort of
production flow up until the moment we
return our proposal
to the client.  Let's test it out right away with
a real brief.  Scope of work,
touchpoints, sector, estimated budget.
We paste the brief here, the tool tells us which
team will work on the project.
We entered the skills for each one,
then all the prospects who followed
as proposals.  Here we see that Garbarino
has 9 free hours a week.  Giulia
Garavaglia too and we do general
briefings for each role.  Here is
basically a recup of what
the PM has to do.  Here are all the phases of the
project.  We generate the plan and here
we have our project Gant.
[applause] The
third team, led by Nicolò, Talent
Manager, has created a system for
managing emails, especially useful
when you have dozens of creators to manage. It
also gives you a nice summary
divided by priority and a report to give
to your boss and your talents.  He reads
all our emails, explains
what's urgent,
prioritizes them, and helps us with
replies.  For
example, if a creator or brand asks us for
a campaign report, we can
easily create a report that we can
download and send to them.   The
fourth team, presented by Francesco
Russo, Head of Originals, developed a
tool to manage the
production process, from
equipment rental to supplier management
.  there is an AI agent.  Three
concrete problems, essentially, that we
want to solve immediately are
dispersed assets, time wasted on
useless alignments and
obviously a whole series of
useless revisions.  Ladies and gentlemen, aura.
First of all, we have the entire list,
we can also search by role, but
also by name.  Then we have an
equipment section which is my favorite.
From Aura we can book
independently.  For example, I want a
table, an easel, I'll book them.
We also have the entire inventory below.   There
can be no overlapping
productions needing the
same equipment at the same time
this way.  But all this
becomes a bit cumbersome, so
we thought about implementing a
chatbot.  We can also ask him to
book both
equipment and the study room directly from the chatbot.  Fifth
team presented by Alberto, my
[music] talent manager who has to manage
a lot of
commercial requests so with the team they
created a solution that automates
commercial flows and puts them
directly into our CRM.
More and more leads are coming in from
all sides, both from the
commercial side and from the individual
talents.  Inside there is already the name
of the company, the name of the person,
there is also the reference email.  Beyond
the qualification part, there is also the
contract part that is theoretically
activated via a Slack message when
the deal arrives for signing.  Then you can
generate the client contract, the
talent contract, or both
together.
One last thing we've implemented
is a Telegram message sent
to our talent with
commercial updates on how
their projects are going.
Essentially, we'll have one report that goes
to the talent manager and the other directly
to the talent, what has come in, what
we've closed and therefore he's happy and
calm about his progress.   The
sixth team, presented by Elisa
Commerciale, has come up with a solution
that starts from the client's brief,
aligns everything internally and already produces
a brief to give to the creators we
mediate.  Once I or
another member of the sales team
completes the call, the program
imports the Gemini notes.  There is a
seven-point summary of the brief, which
also reaches all the relevant stakeholders who
must receive this brief
directly via email.  We have a
second dashboard, create an
Outreach email.  It actually automates
within Pipe Drive as well.  The talents arrive with the entire
creative brief.
Seventh team presented by Emanuele who
holds the record for the person who has made the
highest number of offsites in Flatmates.
He has created a system that automates the
communication and administration of all
invoice-related projects.  In fact, it's a
ball where we report on tens or
hundreds of small [music] projects
that we do with a lot of creators.   We're
talking about billing here, even though it
's 11:30.  Are you resisting?  In agencies,
every account dreads the day when invoices are due at the end of the month
.  It's a process that
is still very cumbersome, super
manual, you waste half a day on it.  There is
a flat button.
He asks us to generate recap.  With one click, it
sends you the draft of the email
to the administration with everyone in copy, it
gives you a summary of what is included,
then creates a summary for you as
formatted as Monica the client wants it.  [applause]
For many projects we have bonuses to
calculate.  We made it so that
the YouTube API automatically calculated
the views and the bonus.   The
eighth team, presented by Francesca
Frachi of the studio, has devised a
solution that, when
a tender proposal arrives, already creates a
presentation with the proposal ideas
based on all our previous
proposals.   Once
the brief for the tender arrives from the client
, he gives us a
tender presentation as output.  There will be a
link to the calendar of the people
involved.  We've put together all the roles
of the people within the team, the
case studies, so all the stuff
we've already worked on and, above all, the
reference briefs for each race with output we've
created in the past for that
race.  We can upload a PDF
by filling in a series of fields below, reading from the brief
.
Thank you.  The ninth and final team, presented by
Gigi, our
communications man, has created a system that
helps new people
onboard the company and
quickly understand where to turn and how it
works.
Good Vitto is registering, you're
new it gives you a general overview of
everything, responsible is eh frausso.  And then
the various pockets, the various emails.
Let's solve it, like Sami has a problem with
his badge, our chatbot
will answer us.  which is a central brain
to which you can ask anything.
At the end of the evening, all the projects
were archived and will be
analyzed more calmly to understand what
actually makes sense to put into
production and what doesn't.  In 24 hours you can
code a prototype at most, but
putting it into actual production still
requires expert people and a little more
time.  But all the solutions were
valid.  They all really
amazed me.  Not even one shirkers.  But
there's no time to rant because the
next day, in the snow,
even though it was June, we drove back
to Milan to get to
the YouTube Festival I'd
been invited to, YouTube's event for
all advertisers.
Thank you because being on this side is
different because I am a
regular listener of yours.  Also being able to
advertise with creators on YouTube.
Besides the other creators, I was there too.
I
am Marcello Lascani, born in 1997, a
YouTuber, a small entrepreneur.
At that point finally home.
Good morning friends, it's already Thursday, I didn't
even realize, the week
flew by and it's one of the rare days I
wake up at home.  Every year I say
this year I'm more stable, I travel
less, I focus on things,
punctually it's not true.  But I use the little
time I have at home to make small
upgrades.  In fact, as you remember,
this is a brand new house.  I've been
here since October now.  By watching TikTok I
learned how to make my bed like a TikToker.   I do
n't iron the blanket because I'm not
crazy, but it makes me feel really good to
be able to do this stuff.  I changed
the curtains but they still drag on the floor
because my ceiling is
surprisingly low.  I have 2.60 m of
ceiling that I recover with the terrace.  I
put curtains throughout the rest of the
house, here it's a little higher, so they don't
rub.  I also put the rug
under the kitchen table, this is
the video corner that we use a lot.
And here I had some more
furniture sent to me because the truth is that after
I did the first upgrade of the house
that I finished more or less when it was
habitable, I stopped doing
upgrades because I had too many things to
do and that's not good because a
lot of things are missing.  The cabinet behind the
sofa is missing, the cabinet where I put
the mirror is missing, I have to change all the
clicks, I want to put a few paintings,
including one over the bed, the
mirror here, this table moves,
a series of things.  You'll say, "But why
are you so dark? Because it's hot and
so I closed up the whole house. Up here is
the little terrace that I'm using every
time I'm home. Oh, the curtains
that IKEA put in for me have all fallen down,
so when people in the comments
wrote to me, "Marcello, is
this terrace going to be really hard to maintain
?" Well, you were right, I haven't
tidied it up, it's a bit of a mess.
Since I installed the automatic
irrigation system, the dead bamboo is
revitalizing, it's growing from the
bottom. I haven't even looked after the vegetable garden
once, but it rained every now and then and
so after it died it has reborn on its
own. There are cherry tomatoes, there are
cherry tomatoes. All in all, despite the
mess, that is, well-being, I love having
breakfast here and taking a few
calls from here, those rare times
I'm at home, and having a few dinners here.
[music]
In the meantime, the team from Livino has
returned home, it's truly been a
beautiful site. Every year I  I say,
but how is it possible that we will be able to make
a more beautiful site than this when there will be
many more of us, we will know each other
less, we will be a more serious organization
and every year we succeed?
[music]
Where are we right now?
We are at the SPM at the
Oltramare exhibition in Naples. I'm about to give my
speech. It will consist of an interview
with Riccardo. This is the backstage.
The long one
is a VIP longed for pizzas.
There they are. We are about to go on stage at
the Sfim. There are 500 people
waiting for us and we have all the time in the
world. Right. What do they say? Right. That
Yes, of course.
How nice of you to interview me.
They know Marcella Scani, I think everyone,
by hand.
Yes. How many of you like
Marcello's new moustache by show of hands?
Eh eh not many. A bit few. I
made them on purpose in honor
of this spam. [laughter]
For this spam compared to before when
I had my continuous pack, I
got rid of that and  I'm making my own
fantastic fort where I don't add
anything else, I keep it there so I know I do
n't have to add anything else to
traditional markets. How many people in
Italy, apart from you, listen to a 40-
minute interview with an entrepreneur,
no more than I already watch on my
YouTube channel?
Marcello Ascani.
You thought I was retired,
but here I am, toiling away day after
day and filling my weeks with
endless commitments. See you in the
next vlogs if I have the time and opportunity to
vlog.